Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives: Small Photograph Collections ALBA.PHOTO.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series X: Ely J. Sack Collection
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (r) and ? (l), Valencia, Dec 1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (r) and ? (l), Barcelona, Apr 1938-May 1938 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (r), ?, ?, Catalonia, Jun 1938 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, Ely Sack (center, with cane) and 18 Unidentified Men, Spain, Jul 1938 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sack, Ely: at the Beach, Mataró, Jul 1938 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sack, Ely: Portraits, Catalonia and Valencia, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sack, Ely: with Edith Sack, Jan 1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sack, Ely: with Edith Sack and Louise Stone, Jan 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sack, Ely: with Parents [?], Aug 1938 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Series XI: Mildred Rackley Collection
  - Ambulance, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Medical Personnel: Tsvetan Angelov Kristanov (a.k.a. Oscar Telge), Edward Barsky [?], Wilhelm Holst, Eve Merriman, Stanislaus Rubint, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series XII: Leon Torgoff Collection
  - Torgoff, Leon: Childhood, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Torgoff, Leon: Childhood with Carl Torgoff and Irving "Togy" Torgoff, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Torgoff, Leon: with Jada [Torgoff?], undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Negative: Leon Torgoff with Wife, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series XIII: Neil Wesson Collection
  - At the Front: Non-Combat, Neil Wesson, Sam ?, Andrew Pape, Sid Horowitz, Jose Baldugne, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - At the Front: Non-Combat, Six Soldiers and Train, Valencia, Nov 13, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation, WWII, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Buildings: Straussberg, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Dachau Concentration Camp: Survivors and Victims, Apr 1945 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Damaged Buildings, [Spain], ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Spanish Civilians: Leana, Aug 9, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Spanish Civilians: Leana and ?, Aug 11, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Spanish Civilians: Leana with Two Unidentified Men, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Spanish Civilians: Rafa and ?, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Spanish Civilians: Susri, Portrait, Sep 1, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Spanish Villages: Street Scenes, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Veterans: Les Rowlson, Dave Mates, Mr. Penn, Marion Noble, Bob Taylor, Nate Wesson, Bob Nagle, Sam Carsman, Saul Wellman, Sid Lynn, U.S., undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Veterans and Families: Millie Thayer, Don Thayer, Bob Raven, Ruth Wesson, Luba Brisker, Sara Goldblatt, the Tutoloff boy, Saul Birnbaum, German Democratic Republic, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Wesson, Neil: At the Front, Non-Combat, with ?, WWII, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Wesson, Neil: Behind the Lines, Daily Life of the Soldiers, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Wesson, Neil: Behind the Lines, Rest and Relaxation, undated, Aug 12, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Wesson, Neil: Behind the Lines, Rest and Relaxation with Robert Merriman and Alfred Balsa, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Wesson, Neil: Dolores Ibarruri's House with Ruth Wesson, Luba Brisker, Alva Bessie, Hy Rassner, Ibarurri, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Wesson, Neil: Rest and Relaxation, with Teddy ?, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Wesson, Neil: Rest and Relaxation, with ?, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Wesson, Neil: En Route to Spain with 16 Unidentified Men, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Wesson, Neil: On the Autobahn, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Wesson, Neil: Portraits, Spain, undated, Nov 23, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Wesson, Neil: Portraits, WWII, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Wesson, Neil: with Bob Raven and Don Thayer, German Democratic Republic, [1961] (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Wesson, Neil: with Sarah Wesson, Camp Crowder, MO, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Wesson, Neil: with Six Veterans, post-SCW, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Wolfgang, Laura: Childhood, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Series XIV: Paul Wendorf Collection
  - At the Front: Combat, Paul Wendorf Firing Machine Gun and ?, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Behind the Lines: Rest and Relaxation: Paul Wendorf and ?, ca.1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Proletarian Monument [Spain], undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Series XV: Elias Begelman Collection
  - Begelman, Elias: Portrait, Spain, ca.1938 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Dorf, Artur: Portrait, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Series XVI: Howard Goddard Collection
  - Goddard, Howard: En Route to Spain with Yale Stuart (Yale Skolnik) and Six Unidentified Men, ca.1937-1983 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Sixtieth Anniversary Homenaje: Spain, Nov 1996 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Valledor, Jose: with Bill Alexander and ?, London, Jul 1985 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Valledor, Jose: with ? and ?, London, Jul 1985 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Series XVII: Miriam Sigel Collection
  - Individual: Unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sigel, Paul: Portrait, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Tishup, Victor: Portrait, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Negative: Paul Sigel, Portrait, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series XVIII: Frank C. Costanzo Collection
  - Costanzo, Frank C.: Portrait, [Spain], ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series XIX: George Chaiken Collection
  - Jimenez, Pedro: Portrait, Oct 1928 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Children: Refugees, ca.1937-1938, Mar 3, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series XX: Sylvia Boehm Acker Collection
  - Boehm, George: Portrait, Paris, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Boehm, George: Portrait, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series XXI: Robert Colodny Collection
  - At the Front: American Volunteers with Pre-WWI Non-Recoil Cannon, Feb 1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - At the Front: "Chato" (Snub-Nose) Soviet Fighter Plane, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - At the Front: U.S. Volunteers in Winter Gear, Spain, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, American Kitchen Crew, Teruel, Feb 1938 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life of the Soldiers, Mitchell Digges (l), Dave Doran (r) with Armored Vehicle, Teruel, Jan 1938 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bottcher, Herman: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cullinen, George: Portrait, N.Y., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Keller, Frida: with Typewriter, Potsdam, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Martin, Fredericka: with Francis Patai, Cuernavaca, Mexico, Aug 1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Memorial to Victims of Spanish Fascism, Spain, Sep 27, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Shaker, Kenneth: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Temple, Lenore: with Rose Freed, Villa Paz, Spain, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 20a)
  - Wheeler, Bill: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Wolff, Milton: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series XXII: James Bernard Rucker Collection
  - Spain: Fuencarral, Premier Regiment de Tren (JR at Top Right, with Cap), 1938 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 317th Medical Battalion of the 92nd Infantry, Company D., 1940s (Box 3, Folder 23a)
  - Decoration Day: James Rucker and President of the United Negro Veterans, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Series XXIII: Martin Friedman Collection
  - Friedman, Martin: Portrait, Spain, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Friedman, Martin: Portrait, U.S., undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Series XXIV: Edward Carter Collection
  - Carter, Edward: Portrait, WWII, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Carter, Edward: with Submachine Gun, Wallerstein, Germany, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Container Ship: SSG Edward A. Carter Jr., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Series XXV: Mito Kruth Collection
  - ?, Clara, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - ?, Erin: with Two Unidentified Men, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Groups: Unidentified, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Kaplan, Nat: In U.S., 1920s (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - ?, Karl: In U.s., 1920s (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Kruth, Mito: Portraits, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Kruth, Mito: with Family, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Kruth, Mito: with Helen Leiviska, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Helen Leiviska: with Family and Friends, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Marcus, Elmer: Portrait and with Esther ? and Martha ?, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Panorama: Stockholm, Sweden, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Vermont Countryside, 1924, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - ?, Walter and Unidentified Man, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Scrapbook: Photocopy, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Series XXVI: Irving Jenkins Collection
  - Cathedral: Notre Dame, Paris, 1930s (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Danchik, Bernie: Barcelona and Paris, [1936] (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Government Army/Militias: Marching, Barcelona, Jul 1936 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Group: Unidentified, Barcelona, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Jenkins, Irving: with Bernie Danchik, [1936] (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Jenkins, Irving: with Bernie Danchik and Dolores Tucker, [1936] (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Jenkins, Irving: Hawaii, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - People's Olympics: Olympians in Paris (after Barcelona), [1936] (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Political Demonstration/Rally: Barcelona, Jul 1936 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Steamship, including Shipboard Image with 3 Olympians, [1936] (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Street Scenes: Barcelona, Jul 1936 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Street Scenes: Paris, [1936] (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Tucker, Dorothy: Barcelona and Paris, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Series XXVII: Benjamin Leider Collection
  - Groups, ca.1936 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Portraits: Benjamin Leider, ca.1936 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Portrait: Benjamin Leider, ca.1936 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Demonstration [New York City]: With Sign/Poster of Benjamin Leider, ca.1937 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Series XXVIII: Douglas Wayne Male Collection
  - Group: Maurice Hawkins, "Ed" "Me," "Vince", ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Group of Spanish Soldiers, with Sterling Rochester, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Sliwon, Boleslaw, with Others: Horseplay - Pretending to Make a Film, ca.1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Series XXIX: Milton White Collection
  - Camp Ridgedale Group Portrait, May 30, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Roffman, Joe: Portrait, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Second World War: Crashed B-26, [early 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Second World War Group Portraits, 1945, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Transparency of "Someone Talked" Poster, [early 1940s] (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Unidentified [Relatives?], undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - White, Milton, Jun 6, 1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Series XXX: Robert Munson Taylor Collection
  - Charlie [?], Robert Taylor, Bill Ireland, Harry Fellman, [?] Benson, [?] Swinnerton (Alicante, Spain), [1937?] (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Company Staff of the First Infantry Company of the Lincoln Brigade: Eli Begelman, Paul Burns, Bill Hallowell, Robert Taylor, and Johnny Power [includes letter from Paul Burns], [circa 1937-1938] (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Taylor, Bob with Upraised Fist (communist salute) Returning from Spain on French Liner L'Havre [with two others], 1939 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Parade in New York City (Moe Fishman, Len Levenson, Leonard Lamb, Bill Van Felix and Vaughn Love), Jun 1984 (Box 3, Folder 74)